Painting Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- Painting Italy (Box 209)
  - Known Artists (Box 212)
    - BRONZINO, Agnolo, 1503-1572 (Box 226–227)
      - Naples (Box 227)
      - New York (Box 227)
      - Paris (Box 227)
      - Rome (Box 227)
      - Washington (Box 227)
    - BUGIARDINI, Giuliano di Pietro di Simone, 1475-1554 (Box 227)
    - BUONCONSIGLIO, Giovanni, fl. 1495-1497 to 1535-1537 (Box 227)
    - BURRI, Alberto, 1915-1995 (Box 227)
    - BUTINONE, Bernardino Jacobi, 1435-1436 to 1506-1508 (Box 227)
    - CAIRO, Francesco del, 1598-1674 (Box 227)
    - CALDARA, Polidoro (Box 227)
    - CALIARI, Benedetto, 1538-1598 (Box 227)
    - CALIARI, Carlo, 1570-1596 (Box 227)
    - CAMBIASO, Luca, 1527-1585 (Box 227)
      - Genoa (Box 227)
    - CAMPAGNOLA, Domenico, 1500-1564 (Box 227)
    - CAMPI, Antonio, 1524-1587 (Box 227)
    - CAMPIGLI, Massimo, 1895- (Box 227)
    - CAMUCCINI, Vencenzo, 1771-1844 (Box 227)
    - CANAL, Antonio, 1697-1768 (Box 227–228)
      - Drawings (Box 227–228)
      - Paintings (Box 227–228)
        - Hartford (Box 227–228)
        - London (Box 227–228)
        - Naples (Box 227–228)
        - Venice (Box 227–228)
        - Washington (Box 227–228)
    - CANALETTO, Antonio Canal (Box 227–228)
    - CANALETTO, Bernardo Bellotto (Box 228)
    - CANLASSI, Guido, 1601-1681 (Box 228)
    - CANTARINI, Simon, 1612-1648 (Box 228)
    - CANUTE, Domenico Maria, 1620-1684 (Box 228)
    - CAPOGROSSI, Giuseppe, 1900- (Box 228)
    - CAPPONI, Raffaelio, 1466-1476 to 1524 (Box 228)
    - CARACCICLO, Giovanni B., 1570-1637 (Box 228)
    - CARAVAGGIO, Michelangelo Merisi da, 1571-1610 (Box 228–229)
      - Card Cheaters (Box 229)
      - Berlin (Box 229)
      - Florence (Box 229)
      - Genoa (Box 229)
      - Leningrad (Box 229)
      - London (Box 229)
      - Messina (Box 229)
      - Milan (Box 229)
      - New York (Box 229)
      - Paris (Box 229)
      - Rome (Box 229)
        - Borghese Gallery (Box 229)
          - Box with Basket of Fruit (Box 229)
        - Doria Gallery (Box 229)
        - S. Agostino (Box 229)
        - S. Luigi dei Francesi (Box 229)
          - Martyrdom of S. Matthew (Box 229)
          - Vocation of S. Matthew (Box 229)
        - S. Maria del Popolo (Box 229)
        - Vatican (Box 229)
      - Syracuse (Box 229)
      - Vienna (Box 229)
      - Washington (Box 229)
    - CARIANI, Giovanni de' Busi, fl. 1509-1547 (Box 229)
    - CARLEVARIS, Luca, 1665-1731 (Box 229)
    - CARNEVALE (Box 229)
    - CAROTO, Giovanni Francesco, 1478-1482 to 1555 (Box 229)
    - CARPACCIO, Vittore, ca. 1460-ca. 1526 (Box 230)
      - New York (Box 230)
      - Paris (Box 230)
      - Venice (Box 230)
        - Accademia (Box 230)
          - S. Ursula Series (Box 230)
            - I (Box 230)
            - II (Box 230)
            - III (Box 230)
            - IV (Box 230)
            - V (Box 230)
            - VI (Box 230)
            - VII (Box 230)
            - VIII (Box 230)
            - IX (Box 230)
        - Museocivico (Box 230)
        - Scuola di S. Giogio (Box 230)
      - Washington (Box 230)
    - CARRA, Carlo, 1881-1966 (Box 230)
    - CARRACI, Annibale, 1560-1609 (Box 230–231)
      - Drawings (Box 231)
      - Paintings (Box 231)
        - Florence (Box 231)
        - London (Box 231)
        - Naples (Box 231)
        - Paris (Box 231)
        - Rome (Box 231)
          - Farnese Palace (Box 231)
    - CARRACI, Ludovico, 1555-1619 (Box 231)
    - CARRIERA, Rosalba Giovanni, 1675-1757 (Box 232)
    - CASORATI, Felice, 1886- (Box 232)
    - CASTAGNO, Andrea del, ca. 1421-1457 (Box 232–233)
      - Berlin (Box 233)
      - Florence (Box 233)
        - Duomo (Box 233)
        - SS. Annunziata (Box 233)
        - SS. Appolonia (Box 233)
          - Crucifixion with Saints (Box 233)
          - Resurrection, Crucifixion, Entombment (Box 233)
          - Last Supper (Box 233)
          - Heroes and Heroines (Box 233)
          - Pippo Spano (Box 233)
      - London (Box 233)
      - New York (Box 233)
      - Venice (Box 233)
      - Washington (Box 233)
    - CASTELLO, Valerio, 1624-1659 (Box 233)
    - CASTIGLIONE, Giovanni Benedetto, 1609-1664 (Box 233)
    - CATENA, Vincenzo di Biagio, 1470-1531 (Box 233)
    - CATERINO, Veneziano, fl. 1455 (Box 233)
    - CAVALLINO, Bernardo, 1622-1654 (Box 233)
    - CAVEDONE, Giacomo, 1577-1660 (Box 233)
    - CELLINI, Benvenuto, 1500-1571 (Box 233)
    - CENNI di Francesco di Sercenni, fl. 1369-1415 (Box 233)
    - CERESA, Carlo, 1609-1679 (Box 233)
    - CERQUOZZI, Michelangelo, 1602-1660 (Box 233)
    - CERUTI, Giacomo, fl. ca. 1720-1750 (Box 233)
    - CESARI, Giuseppi, 1568-1640 (Box 233)
    - CHIARI, Domenico, fl. 1650 (Box 233)
    - CHIARINI, Marcantonio, 1652-1710 (Box 233)
    - CHIRICO, Giorgio de, 1888-1978 (Box 233)
      - New York (Box 233)
    - CIGNANI, Carlo, 1628-1719 (Box 233)
    - CIGOLI, Ludovico, 1559-1613 (Box 234)
    - CIMA da Conegliano, Giovanni Battista, ca. 1459-1517 (Box 234)
      - Parma (Box 234)
      - Venice (Box 234)
      - Washington (Box 234)
    - CIONE, Andrea di (Orcagana), ca. 1315-1368 (Box 234)
    - CIPPER, Giacomo Francesco (Todeschini), fl. 1710-1736 (Box 234)
    - CIVERCHIO, Vincenzo, 1468-1470 to 1544 (Box 234)
    - CODAZZI, Viviano, 1604-1670 (Box 234)
    - CONCA, Sebastiano, 1676-1680 to 1764 (Box 234)
    - CONTE, Jacopo del, 1510-1598 (Box 234)
    - CONTI, Bernardino dei, 1450-1525 (Box 234)
    - COPPO di Marcovaldo, ca. 1225-after 1276 (Box 234)
      - Pistoia (Box 234)
    - CORRADINI, Bartolomeo (Box 234)
    - CORREGIO, Antonio Allegri, 1494-1534 (Box 234–235)
      - Drawings (Box 235)
      - Paintings (Box 235)
        - Berlin (Box 235)
        - Dresden (Box 235)
          - Holy Night (Adoration) (Box 235)
        - Florence (Box 235)
        - London (Box 235)
        - Madrid (Box 235)
        - New York (Box 235)
        - Paris (Box 235)
        - Parma (Box 235)
          - Gallery (Box 235)
            - Madonna of the Bowl (Box 235)
            - Madonna of S. Jerome (Box 235)
          - Cupola of Cathedral (Box 235)
          - S. Giovanni Evangelista (Box 235)
          - Convent of S. Paolo (Box 235)
        - Rome (Box 235)
        - Vienna (Box 235)
    - CORRODI, Herman David Solomon, 1844-1905 (Box 235)
    - CORTONA, Pietro da, 1596-1669 (Box 236–237)
      - Drawings (Box 237)
      - Paintings (Box 237)
        - Castelfusano Villa Sacchetti (Chigi) (Box 237)
        - Florence (Box 237)
          - Palazzo Pitti (Box 237)
            - Vault Frescoes (Box 237)
            - Ages of Gold, Silver, Copper, Iron (Box 237)
        - Paris (Box 237)
        - Rome (Box 237)
          - Capitoline Gallery (Box 237)
          - Palazzo Barberini (Box 237)
          - Ceiling Frescoes Glorification of Urban VIII's Papacy (Box 237)
          - Palazzo Doria Pamphilia Galleria (Box 237)
          - Palazzo Mattei (Box 237)
          - S. Maria in Vallicella (Box 237)
    - COSSA, Francesco del, ca. 1435-ca. 1477 (Box 237)
      - Ferrara (Box 237)
      - Washington (Box 237)
    - COSTA, Lorenzo di Ottavio, ca.1460-1535 (Box 237)
    - COZZA, Francesco, 1605-1682 (Box 237)
    - COZZARELLI, Guidoccio di Giovanni, 1450-1516 (Box 237)
      - Siena (Box 237)
    - CREDI, Lorenzo, ca. 1456-1536c (Box 237)
      - Drawings (Box 237)
      - Paintings (Box 237–238)
        - Florence (Box 238)
        - Washington (Box 238)
    - CREMONA, Tranquillo (Box 238)
    - CRESPI, Daniele, 1590-1630 (Box 238)
    - CRESPI, Giovanni Battista, 1576-1632 (Box 238)
    - CRESPI, Giuseppe Maria, 1665-1747 (Box 238)
    - CRIVELLI, Carlo, ca. 1430-1495 (Box 238)
      - Berlin (Box 238)
      - Boston (Box 238)
      - Cambridge, MA (Box 238)
      - London (Box 238)
      - Milan (Box 238)
      - New York (Box 238)
      - Rome (Box 238)
      - Washington (Box 238)
    - CRONACA, Simone, 1457-1508 (Box 238)
    - DALMASIO (Box 238)
    - DANDINI, Cesare, 1595-1658 (Box 238)
    - DANIELE da Volterra, 1509-1566 (Box 238)
    - DEFARRARI, Gregorio, 1664-1726 (Box 238)
    - DELLO di Niccola delli, ca.1403-ca.1470 (Box 238)
    - DEODATUS, Orlandi, f. 1288-1337 (Box 238)
    - DIANA, Benedetto, 1460-1525 (Box 238)
    - DIDO MASTER (Box 238)
    - DOLCE, Carlo, 1616-1686 (Box 238–239)
      - Florence (Box 239)
      - Rome (Box 239)
    - DOMENICHINO, Zampieri, 1581-1641 (Box 239)
      - Grottaferrata (Box 239)
      - Paris (Box 239)
      - Rome (Box 239)
        - Borghese Gallery (Box 239)
        - S. Andrea della Valle (Box 239)
    - DOMENICO di Bartolo (Box 239)
      - Perugia (Box 239–240)
      - Siena (Box 240)
        - Ospedale S. Maria della Scala (Box 240)
          - Enlarging the Hospital (Box 240)
          - Pope Grants the Hospital (Box 240)
          - Distribution of Alms (Box 240)
          - Feeding the Poor (Box 240)
          - Orphans and Marriages (Box 240)
          - Treatment of Sick (Box 240)
    - DOMENICO di Michelino, 1417-1491 (Box 240)
    - DOMENICO Veneziano, ca. 1400-1461 (Box 240–241)
      - Berlin (Box 241)
      - Cambridge, England (Box 241)
      - Florence (Box 241)
        - S. Lucia dei Magnoli Altarpiece (Box 241)
      - London (Box 241)
      - Washington (Box 241)
    - DOSSI, Dosso, (Giovanni di Nicolo de Lutero), ca. 1486-1542 (Box 241)
      - Washington (Box 241)
    - ERRI, Bartolomeo degli, fl. 1460-1475 (Box 241)
    - EUSERIO da Sangiorgio, 1465-1470 to 1539 (Box 241)
    - FARINATO, Paolo, 1524-1606 (Box 241)
    - FERRARESE, Galasso (Box 241)
    - FERRARI, Defendente di, 1481-1546 (Box 241)
    - FERRARI, Gaudenzio, 1470-1480 to 1546-1549 (Box 241)
    - FERRARI, Gregorio di, 1644-1726 (Box 241)
    - FETTI, Domenico, 1589-1624 (Box 241)
    - FINIGUERRA, Maso, 1426-1464 (Box 241–242)
    - FIORE, Jacobello del, fl. 1400, d. 1439 (Box 242)
    - FIORENZO di Lorenzo, 1445-1525 (Box 242)
      - Perugia (Box 242)
    - FLIPART, Charles Joseph, 1721-1797 (Box 242)
    - FONTEBASSO, Francesco Salvato, 1709-1769 (Box 242)
    - FOPPA, Vincenzo, 1427-1430 to 1515-1516 (Box 242)
    - FORABOSCO, Girolamo, ca. 1604-1675 (Box 242)
    - FOSCHI, Piero della, fl. ca. 1535 (Box 242)
    - FRANCESCA, Piero della, ca. 1415-1492 (Box 242–245)
      - Arezzo (Box 242–245)
        - S. Francesco (Box 242–245)
          - Legend of the True Cross (Box 242–245)
            - Annunciation (Box 242–245)
            - Burying the Wood (Box 242–245)
            - Constantine's Dream (Box 242–245)
            - Constantine's Victory over Maxentius (Box 242–245)
            - Death and Burial of Adam (Box 242–245)
            - Defeat and Death of Chosroys (Box 242–245)
            - Discovery of the Cross (Box 242–245)
            - Heraclus Restores the Cross (Box 242–245)
            - Sheba and Solomon (Box 242–245)
            - Torture of Judas (Box 242–245)
        - Borgo S. Sepulcro (Box 242–245)
          - Resurrection (Box 242–245)
      - Florence (Box 242–245)
        - Uffizi (Box 242–245)
      - London (Box 242–245)
        - National Gallery (Box 242–245)
          - Nativity (Box 242–245)
          - Baptism (Box 242–245)
      - Milan (Box 242–245)
      - Monterchi (Box 242–245)
      - New York (Box 242–245)
      - Perugia (Box 242–245)
      - Rimini (Box 242–245)
      - Urbino (Box 245)
        - Flagellation (Box 245)
        - Perspective Diagrams of Francesca's Works by John Spenser (Box 245)
      - Washington (Box 245)
    - FRANCESCHINI, Baldassare, 1611-1689 (Box 245)
    - FRANCESCHINI, Marc Antonio, 1648-1729 (Box 245)
    - FRANCESCO d' Antonio Banchi (Box 245)
    - FRANCESCO dei Franceschi, fl. ca. 1450-1459 (Box 245)
    - FRANCESCO di Giorgio Martini, 1439-1502 (Box 245)
      - Drawings (Box 245)
      - Paintings (Box 245)
        - New York (Box 245)
        - Siena (Box 245)
          - Accademia (Box 245)
          - Palazzo Pubblico (Box 245)
    - FRANCIA (Box 245)
    - FRANCIABIGIO, ca. 1482-1525 (Box 245)
    - FRATINO, Giovanni, fl. ca. 1538-1560 (Box 245)
    - FUMANI, Giovanni Antonio, 1643-1710 (Box 245)
    - FUNGAI, Bernardino, 1460-1516 (Box 246)
    - FURINI, Francesco, 1600-1604 to 1646-1649 (Box 246)
    - GALLINO, Cayetano, 1804-1884 (Box 246)
    - GARGIULO, Domenico, 1612-1675 (Box 246)
    - GAROFALO, Benevenuto Tisi Da, 1481-1559 (Box 246)
      - New York (Box 246)
      - Rome (Box 246)
    - GAULLI, Giovanni Battista, 1639-1709 (Box 246)
    - GENGA, Girolamo (Box 246)
    - GENTILESCHI, Artemisia, 1593-ca. 1651 (Box 246)
    - GENTILESCHI, Orazio, 1563-1639 (Box 246)
    - GHERARDI, Filippo, 1643-1704 (Box 246)
    - GHIRLANDAIO, David, 1452-1525 (Box 246)
    - GHIRLANDAIO, Domenico, 1449-1494 (Box 246)
      [Boxes 246-248]
      - Florence (Box 246)
        - Innocenti (Box 246)
        - Ognissanti (Box 246)
          - S. Jerome (Box 247)
        - Uffizi (Box 247)
        - Palazzo Vecchio (Box 247)
        - S. Maria Novella (Box 247)
          - Life of the Virgin (Box 247)
          - Life of John the Baptist (Box 247)
        - S. Marco (Box 247)
        - S. Trinita (Box 247)
      - London (Box 248)
      - New Haven (Box 248)
      - New York (Box 248)
      - Paris (Box 248)
      - Rome (Box 248)
      - S. Gimignano (Box 248)
    - GHIRLANDAIO (school of) (Box 248)
    - GHIRLANDAIO, Ridolfo, 1483-1561 (Box 248)
    - GHISLANDI, Vittore (Box 248)
    - GIAMBONO, see BONO (Box 248)
    - GIAMPIETRINO, ca. 1500-1560 (Box 248)
    - GIAN Francesco de' Maineri, fl. 1489-1506 (Box 248)
    - GIANUSI, Antonio, fl. 1700-1750 (Box 248)
    - GIHIGNANI, Ludovico, 1643-1691 (Box 248)
    - GIMIGNANI, Giacinto, 1611-168 (Box 248)
    - GIOLFINO, Niccolo, 1476-1555 (Box 248)
    - GIORDANO, Luca, 1632-1705 (Box 248)
    - GIORGIONE, Il, 1477-1510 (Box 248–249)
      - Boston (Box 249)
      - Budapest (Box 249)
      - Castelfranco (Box 249)
      - Dresden (Box 249)
      - Florence (Box 249)
      - New York (Box 249)
      - Paris (Box 249)
      - Venice (Box 249)
      - Vienna (Box 249)
      - Washington (Box 249)
    - GIOVANNI di Giacomo Gavazzi, fl. ca. 1575-1600 (Box 249)
    - GIOVANNI di Paolo, fl. ca. 1420, d. 1482 (Box 250)
      - Baltimore (Box 250)
      - Berlin (Box 250)
      - Boston (Box 250)
      - Cambridge (Box 250)
      - Chicago (Box 250)
      - Colle Val d' Elsa (Box 250)
      - Florence (Box 250)
      - London (Box 250)
      - New Haven (Box 250)
      - New York (Box 250)
      - Paris (Box 250)
      - Philadelphia (Box 250)
      - Pienza (Box 250)
      - Rome (Box 250)
      - Siena (Box 250)
      - Washington (Box 250)
    - GIROLAMO da Carpa (Box 250)
    - GIROLAMO da Cremona, fl. 1467-1483 (Box 250)
    - GIROLAMO da Treviso (elder), ca. 1450-ca. 1490 (Box 250)
    - GIROLAMO da Treviso (younger), 1497-1544 (Box 250)
    - GIROLAMO di Benevenuto Giovanni Delguasta, 1470-1524 (Box 250)
    - GIROLAMO Giovenone, fl. 1513-1555 (Box 250)
    - GIULIO Romano, 1499-1546 (Box 250–251)
      - Drawings (Box 251)
      - Paintings (Box 251)
        - Genoa (Box 251)
        - Madrid (Box 251)
        - Mantua (Box 251)
        - Naples (Box 251)
        - Paris (Box 251)
        - Rome (Box 251)
          - Vatican (Box 251)
        - Washington (Box 251)
    - GIUSTO d' Andrea, fl. 1424-1498 (Box 251)
    - GRANACCI, Francesco, 1469-1543 (Box 251)
    - GREGORIO di Cecco di Luca (Box 251)
    - GRIMALDI, Giovanni Francesco, 1606-1680 (Box 251)
    - GUALTIERI di Giovanni (Box 251)
    - GUARDI, Francesco, 1712-1793 (Box 251–252)
      - Drawings (Box 252)
      - Paintings (Box 252)
        - Berlin (Box 252)
        - London (Box 252)
        - Milan (Box 252)
        - New York (Box 252)
        - Paris (Box 252)
        - Venice (Box 252)
        - Washington (Box 252)
    - GUERCINO, (Giovanni Francesco Barbieri), 1591-1666 (Box 252–253)
      - Bologna (Box 253)
      - Florence (Box 253)
      - London (Box 253)
      - Milan (Box 253)
      - Paris (Box 253)
      - Piacenza (Box 253)
      - Rome (Box 253)
        - Villa Ludovisi (Box 253)
        - Vatican (Box 253)
    - GUGLIELMI, Gregorio, 1714-1773 (Box 253)
    - GUIDO da Siena, fl. 1221-1281? (Box 253)
    - IBI, Sinibaldo, 1475-1550 (Box 253)
    - INNOCENZO da Imola, ca. 1490-ca. 1550 (Box 253)
    - JACOPO del Casentino, 1278-1358 (Box 253)
    - JOLLI, Antonio, 1700-1777 (Box 253)
    - JUVARA (Box 253)
    - LANDI, Neroccio di, 1447-1500 (Box 253–254)
      - Florence (Box 254)
      - Magliano (Box 254)
      - New Haven (Box 254)
      - New York (Box 254)
      - Siena (Box 254)
      - Washington (Box 254)
    - LANDINI, Jacopo del Casentino, 1297-1358 (Box 254)
    - LANFRANCO, Giovanni, 1580-1581 to 1647 (Box 254)
    - LANTTANZIO da Rimini (Box 254)
    - LAURANA, Luciano, ca. 1420-1479 (Box 254–255)
    - LEONARDO da Vinci, 1452-1519 (Box 255–260)
      - Architecture, see ARCHITECTURE RENAISSANCE ITALY GENERAL (Box 255)
      - General (Box 255)
      - Drawings (Box 255)
        - Anatomy (Box 255)
        - Animals (Box 255)
        - Drapery (Box 255)
        - Figures (Box 255)
          - Man of Perfect Proportions (Box 256)
        - Hands (Box 256)
        - Heads, Portraits, Caricatures (Box 256)
          - Self-Portrait (Box 256)
        - Landscapes (for Deluges, see Storms) (Box 256)
        - Machines (Box 256)
        - Plants (Box 257)
        - Storms (Deluges) (Box 257)
        - Study for Adoration of the Magi (Box 257)
        - Study for Adoration of Shepherds (Box 257)
        - Study for Battle of Anghiari (Box 257)
        - Study for Equestrian Monument (Box 257)
        - Studies for the Last Supper (Box 257)
        - Studies for Leda (Box 257)
        - Studies for the Virgin of the Rocks (Box 257)
        - Studies for the Virgin, Child, and S. Anne (Box 257)
        - Virgin with the Cat (Box 257)
        - Virgins (Box 258)
        - Water (Box 258)
      - Paintings (Box 258)
        - Florence (Box 258)
          - Uffizi (Box 258)
            - Adoration of the Magi (Box 258)
            - Annunciation (Box 258)
          - Leningrad (Box 258)
          - London (Box 258)
          - Milan (Box 258)
            - S. Maria delle Grazie (Box 258)
          - Munich (Box 259)
          - Paris (Box 259)
            - Mona Lisa (Box 259)
            - S. John the Baptist (Box 259)
            - Virgin, Child, and S. Anne (Box 259)
            - Virgin of the Rocks (Box 259)
          - Rome (Box 259)
            - Vatican (Box 259)
          - Washington (Box 259)
    - LEONARDO, copy after (Box 259–260)
      - Battle of Anghiari copies (Box 260)
    - LEONARDO, follower of (Box 260)
    - LEONI, Ottavio Mario, 1578-1630 (Box 260)
    - LIBRI, Girolamo dai, 1474-1555 (Box 260)
    - LICINIO, Bernardino, ca. 1480-ca. 1560 (Box 260)
    - LIPPI, Filippino, 1457-1460 to 1504-1505 (Box 260–261)
      - Florence (Box 261)
        - Badia (Box 261)
        - S. Maria del Carmine (Box 261)
          - Peter in Prison (Box 261)
          - Trial and Crucifixion (Box 261)
        - S. Maria Novella (Box 261)
        - Uffizi (Box 261)
      - London (Box 261)
      - Rome (Box 261)
      - Washington (Box 261)
    - LIPPI, Fra Filippo di Tomaso, ca. 1406-1459 (Box 261–262)
      - Berlin (Box 262)
      - Cambridge (Box 262)
      - Empoli (Box 262)
      - Florence (Box 262)
        - S. Maria del Carmine (Box 262)
        - Palazzo Pitti (Box 262)
        - Uffizi (Box 262)
      - London (Box 262)
      - Milan (Box 262)
      - Munich (Box 262)
      - New York (Box 262)
      - Paris (Box 262)
      - Prato (Box 262)
      - Rome (Box 262)
      - Spoleto (Box 262)
      - Washington (Box 262)
    - LIPPI, Lorenzo, 1606-1665 (Box 262)
    - LOCATELLI, Andrea, 1660-1695 to 1741? (Box 262)
    - LONGHI, Pietro, 1702-1785 (Box 262)
      - Bergamo (Box 262)
      - New York (Box 262)
      - Venice (Box 262)
    - LORENZO, d' Alessandro da Sanservino (Box 262)
    - LOTTO, Lorenzo, ca. 1480-1556 (Box 262–263)
      - Bergamo (Box 263)
      - Berlin (Box 263)
      - Brescia (Box 263)
      - Cambridge (Box 263)
      - Cingoli (Box 263)
      - Cleveland (Box 263)
      - Florence (Box 263)
      - Jesi (Iesi) (Box 263)
      - London (Box 263)
      - Madrid (Box 263)
      - Milan (Box 263)
      - Monte San Guisto (Box 263)
      - Munich (Box 263)
      - Naples (Box 263)
      - New York (Box 263)
      - Paris (Box 263)
      - Recanati (Box 263)
      - Rome (Box 263)
      - Vienna (Box 263)
      - Washington (Box 263)
    - LUINI, Bernardino, 1465-1475 to 1532 (Box 263)
      - London (Box 263)
      - Lugano (Box 263)
      - Madrid (Box 263)
      - Milan (Box 263)
        - Brera (Box 263)
        - Poldi-Pezzoli (Box 263)
        - S. Maurizio (Box 263)
      - Paris (Box 263)
      - Saronno (Box 263)
      - Washington (Box 263)
    - MACCHIETTI, Girolamo (Box 263)
    - MACHIAVELLI, Zanobi di Jacopo, 1416-1479 (Box 263)
    - MAFFEI, Francesco, ca. 1620-1660 (Box 263)
    - MAGNASCO, Alessandro, 1681-1749 (Box 264)
      - Bassano (Box 264)
      - Boston (Box 264)
      - Cleveland (Box 264)
      - Genoa (Box 264)
      - Hartford (Box 264)
      - New Haven (Box 264)
      - New York (Box 264)
      - Milan (Box 264)
      - Venice (Box 264)
      - Worcester (Box 264)
    - MAINARDI, Sebastiano da Bartolo, 1460 to 1513-1515 (Box 264)
    - MAINERI, Francesco de', fl. 1489-1506 (Box 264)
    - MANCINI, F. (Box 264)
    - MANFREDI, Bartolomeo, 1580-1620 (Box 264)
    - MANNOZI, Giovanni, 1592-1630 (Box 264)
    - MANSUETI, Giovanni di Niccolo, 1485-1527 (Box 264)
    - MANTEGNA, Andrea, 1431-1506 (Box 264–266)
      - Drawings (Box 265)
      - Paintings (Box 265)
        - Bergamo (Box 265)
        - Berlin (Box 265)
        - Cincinatti (Box 265)
        - Cleveland (Box 265)
        - Dresden (Box 265)
        - Dublin (Box 265)
        - Florence (Box 265)
          - Uffizi (Box 265)
        - Hampton Court (Box 265)
        - London (Box 265)
          - National Gallery (Box 265)
        - Mantua (Box 265)
          - Palazzo Ducale (Box 265)
            - Return of Cardinal Gonzaga (Box 265)
            - Cherubs (Box 265)
        - Milan (Box 265)
        - Padua (Box 265)
        - Paris (Box 265)
          - Louvre (Box 265)
        - Venice (Box 266)
          - Accademia (Box 266)
        - Verona (Box 266)
        - Vienna (Box 266)
        - Washington (Box 266)
    - MANTEGNA, Andrea, school of (Box 266)
    - MANTOVANO, Rinaldo (Box 266)
    - MARATTI, Carlo, 1625-1713 (Box 266)
    - MARCHESI, Girolamo ("Girolamo da Cotignola"), 1480-1550 (Box 266)
    - MARGARITONE, d' Arezzo, 1216-1293 (Box 266)
    - MARIESCHI, Jacopo di Paolo, 1711-1794 (Box 266)
    - MARINI, Marino, 1901- (Box 266)
    - MARZIALE, Marco, 1493-1507 (Box 266)
    - MASACCIO, di Giovanni di Simone (Tomasoguido), 1401-1402 to 1428-1429 (Box 266)
      - Berlin (Box 266)
        - Predella from Pisa (Box 266)
        - Predella: Adoration of the Magi (Box 266)
        - Predella: Crucifixion of Peter (Box 266)
        - Predella: Martyrdome of John the Baptist (Box 266)
      - Boston (Box 266)
      - Florence (Box 267)
        - S. Maria del Carmine (Box 267)
          - Expulsion (Box 267)
          - Tribute Money (Box 267)
            - Details (Box 267)
          - S. Peter Curing the Sick with His Shadow (Box 267)
          - S. Peter giving Alms to the Faithful (Box 267)
          - S. Peter Raising the King's Son (Box 267)
        - S. Maria Novella (Box 267–268)
          - Trinity (Box 268)
            - Details (Box 268)
            - Diagrams and Perspectives (Box 268)
            - After Cleaning (Box 268)
        - Uffizi (Box 268)
      - London (Box 268)
        - Madonna and Child Enthroned (Box 268)
        - SS. Jerome and John the Baptist (Box 268)
      - Naples (Box 268)
      - Pisa (Box 268)
      - Reggello (Box 268)
      - Washington (Box 268)
    - MASACCIO, school of (Box 268)